Guide to the Shackleton Family Collection, 1914-1921
Shackleton Family Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Shackleton Family Collection, 1914-1921
37-05-3133
Shackleton Family
3.0 cubic ft.
Scrapbooks, photographs, film, classnotes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scrapbooks, photos and films from Mary E. Moore Shackleton and Horace Shackleton. Most material relates to their experiences as students at Cornell University but there is also material related to the Shackleton/Moore families
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Mary Eastman Moore (Cornell University Class of 1920) was the daughter of Veranus A. Moore, dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine. She graduated from Cornell in 1920 and married Horace E. Shackleton who graduated from Cornell in 1919. Horace Shackleton was an employee of the Grange League Federation and Mary Shackleton worked in Statler Hall.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Two scrapbooks of Mary E. Moore from Ithaca High School and Cornell University including photographs, programs, memorabilia, and clippings. Several notebooks from Mary E. Moore's classwork at Cornell, many from classes at the New York State College of Home Economics. Two Cornell University scrapbooks of Horace E. Shackleton and his photograph album of Cornell scenes. Also 35 reels of 8 mm. movie film, primarily of Cornell athletic events, but also some family home movies and one copy of an "Our Gang" film.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Shackleton, Mary Moore.; Shackleton, Horace E.; Cornell University. Class of 1919.; Cornell University. Class of 1920.; Cornell University--Pictorial works.; New York State College of Home Economics.
Subjects:
Women college students--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Photographs.; Motion pictures (visual works)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
The scrapbooks and film were given to the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections by the DeWitt Historical Society in 2001. Mary Moore's class notes were separated from the Veranus Moore papers in 2004.
RELATED MATERIAL
RMC Collection #51-01-1368. Norman Moore papers, 1919-1994.
RMC Collection #24-01-119. Veranus A. Moore papers, 1836-1958.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Photographs
Series II. Scrapbooks
Series III. Mary Moore's Class Notes
Series IV. Films and Ephemera
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Photographs
  - Horace Shackleton photo album (Box 1)
  - Photos of New York City, including Bellevue Hospital (Box 1)
  - Long landscape picture, including Veranus Moore, of the "American Veterinary Association at Panama Pacific International Expedition, San Francisco, Cal, Sept 3, 1915" (Box 3)
- Series II. Scrapbooks
  - Horace Shackleton's Stunt Book # 11, 1915-1917 (Box 2)
  - Horace Shackleton's Stunt Book # 12, 1917-1919 (Box 2)
  - Mary Moore's "High School and College Days" Scrapbook (Box 4)
  - Mary Moore's Cornell Stunt Book (Box 4)
- Series III. Mary Moore's Class Notes
  - Bacteriology, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Biochemistry, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chemistry 92?, ca. 1918 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chemistry 93, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Design, 1918 - 1919 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dressmaking and Millinary, 1915 - 1916 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - English History, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - First Term, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - H.E. 2, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - H.E. 9, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - H.E. 15, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - H.E. 70, 1919 - 1920 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Health in the Home, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - History, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - History, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - House Planning, 1918 - 1919 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Household Management, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Household Bacteriology, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Human Physiology VI, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Human Physiology VII, 1917 - 1918 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Inorganic Chemistry, 1912 - 1914 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Political Science, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Qualitative Analysis, ca. 1920 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Recipes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Rural Organization, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Rural Organization, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Sixth Grade Sewing, 1906 - 1908 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Textiles, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Zoology, 1917 - 1918 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Zoology, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Chemistry Exam Books, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series IV. Films and Ephemera
  - Films (Box 3)
  - 2 copies of The Cornell Era from 1919 (Box 1)
  - Clipping picturing Veranus Moore, Norman Moore, and Erwin Moore (Box 1)
  - Clipping of 1925 Rotarians (Box 1)